So here is a short lecture
Đây là một bài ngắn
that unfortunately you have to learn for the exam,
mà tiếc là bạn phải học cho kỳ thi,
maybe for one question.
có thể chỉ cho một câu hỏi.
It is a way to do migrations to Aurora MySQL.
Đó là cách để migrate sang Aurora MySQL.
So if you have an RDS database
Nếu bạn có một RDS database
and you want to move it into Aurora MySQL,
và muốn chuyển nó sang Aurora MySQL,
the option number one is to take a database snapshot
tùy chọn đầu tiên là tạo database snapshot
from the RDS MySQL database
từ RDS MySQL
and you restore this snapshot as a MySQL Aurora database.
và restore snapshot đó thành Aurora MySQL.
Potentially, you'll have some downtime
Có thể bạn sẽ có downtime
because you have to stop operations
vì phải dừng hoạt động
on the first MySQL database before migrating to Aurora.
trên MySQL ban đầu trước khi chuyển sang Aurora.
The option number two, which is more continuous,
Tùy chọn thứ hai liên tục hơn
is to use and create an Amazon Aurora Read Replica
là tạo một Amazon Aurora Read Replica
on top of your RDS MySQL.
trên RDS MySQL của bạn.
So it's a possibility indeed.
Đây là khả năng có thể.
And once the Replica lag is zero,
Khi Replica lag bằng 0,
that means that once the Aurora Replica
tức là khi Aurora Replica
has fully caught up with MySQL,
đã bắt kịp MySQL,
you can promote it into its own database cluster.
bạn có thể promote nó thành database cluster riêng.
Now this can take a bit more time
Cách này mất nhiều thời gian hơn
than the database snapshot option
so với phương án snapshot
and cost some money because of the network cost
và tốn chi phí do network cost
that may be associated with this replication.
liên quan đến replication này.
The other option is, if you have a MySQL database
Tùy chọn khác: nếu bạn có MySQL database
that is external to RDS,
bên ngoài RDS,
then you can back it up
bạn có thể backup nó
using the Percona XtraBackup utility.
bằng công cụ Percona XtraBackup.
This will create a backup file and you put it in Amazon S3
Điều này tạo file backup và bạn đặt vào Amazon S3
and then there is an option from Amazon Aurora
và Aurora có tùy chọn
to directly import this backup file
để import trực tiếp file backup
into a new Aurora MySQL DB cluster.
vào một Aurora MySQL DB cluster mới.
Just so you know,
Lưu ý
this only supports the Percona XtraBackup utility.
chỉ hỗ trợ công cụ Percona XtraBackup.
The other option is to use the MySQL Dump utility
Tùy chọn khác là dùng MySQL Dump
to run it against a MySQL database
chạy trên MySQL database
and you would pipe the output of this
và bạn pipe output của nó
into your existing Amazon Aurora database.
vào Amazon Aurora database hiện có.
So this is taking a lot of time
Điều này mất rất nhiều thời gian
and this does not leverage Amazon S3.
và không tận dụng Amazon S3.
And a last option is to use Amazon DMS,
Tùy chọn cuối là dùng Amazon DMS,
if both databases are up and running
nếu cả hai database đều chạy
to do continuous replication between the two databases.
để replicate liên tục giữa hai database.
We do the same process for PostgreSQL,
Chúng ta làm tương tự cho PostgreSQL,
so for RDS, it's pretty much similar.
nên với RDS cũng khá giống.
You have two option to use the database snapshots
Bạn có hai lựa chọn: dùng database snapshot
restored as an Amazon Aurora database
restore thành Amazon Aurora database
or you create an Amazon Aurora Read Replica of PostgreSQL
hoặc tạo Amazon Aurora Read Replica của PostgreSQL
to have to have a Read Replica
để có Read Replica
and then you wait until a replication lag is zero
và chờ đến khi replication lag bằng 0
to promote it into its own database cluster.
để promote thành database cluster riêng.
And if it's an external PostgreSQL database
Nếu đó là PostgreSQL bên ngoài
that you want to migrate to Aurora,
mà bạn muốn migrate sang Aurora,
you can create a backup of it
bạn có thể tạo backup
and then you put the backup in Amazon S3,
và đặt backup vào Amazon S3,
and then you import the data
sau đó bạn import dữ liệu
using the AWS S3 Aurora extension
bằng AWS S3 Aurora extension
and this will create a new database out of it.
và điều này tạo database mới.
And finally, again, you can use DMS to migrate
Cuối cùng, bạn cũng có thể dùng DMS để migrate
from PostgreSQL to Amazon Aurora continuously.
từ PostgreSQL sang Amazon Aurora liên tục.
Okay. That's it for this lecture.
Ok, bài học đến đây là hết.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.
Hy vọng bạn thích và hẹn gặp bạn ở bài học tiếp theo.